A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Faculty records, Scientific Staff Appointments FA1327
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Faculty records, Scientific Staff Appointments
1901-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University.
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA1327
0.19 Cubic Feet 1 half-letter document box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
The majority of the records originated in a notebook entitled "Appointments now held by present and past members of the Scientific Staff of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research since the opening of the laboratories in 1904". The original notebook was discarded due to poor condition. The entries include the following information: Name; Highest degrees earned; Titles and dates of Institute appointments; Appointment succeeding last Institute appointment; and Present or last known appointment or position.
Biographical / Historical
In March 1960 an Office of the Registrar was established to maintain records of faculty and students. This was a function which to this date had been handled by the Dean of Students and through the Office of the President. Earlier records of the scientific staff had been kept in the Office of the Business Manager. The first appointment to the position of Registrar was Marian Lucius who resigned in June 1972.
The functions of the office developed as it became an adjunct to the Office of the President. Reports to the New York State Education Department were made from this office. Various statistical data on institutional facilities, such as the library; the number of degrees granted; subjects and rank of instructional staff were filed through this office to be reported to the State Department of Education. When a program of state-aid to non-public institutions of higher education was established required reports were made each year.
After the resignation of Marian Lucius, Phyllis Viets was appointed and served to June 1974.
Antonia Siddiqi, from the Office of the President, took charge of the funtions of the Office of Faculty and Student records in addition to her work on the Grant Proposals and Grant Programs of the various laboratories. In 1979 Antonia Siddiqi became Secretary to the Board of Trustees as well as Director of the Office of Sponsored Programs with Eleanor Gibson handling much of the routine of Faculty and Student records.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 370
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Pathology and Bacteriology, 1904-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Chemistry, 1910-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Physiology (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Experimental Surgery, 1906-1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Biophysics, 1920-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Departmental Biology, 1954- (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Hospital, 1904-1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Hospital, 1924-1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Hospital, 1934-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Animal and Plant Pathology, 1914-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Scientific Staff Appointments - Various Departments, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, Scientific Staff, c. 1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Record of Memorial Minutes and Related Information for Members and Associate Members, c. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Senior Scientific Staff of the Rockefeller Institute and University, 1901-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)